Finding Aid for the Cornelius Vanderbilt IV Papers
Special Collections and University Archives
John Robert Nelson Papers
1897-1974
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0467
26.03 linear feet
Scope And Content Note
The Cornelius Vanderbilt IV Papers, 1897-1974, include correspondence, manuscripts of writings, lecture materials, reviews of his books and film, personal papers, legal and business documents, photographs, newspaper clippings, and scrapbooks of his various writing and lecture projects. The forty-five boxes of the collection cover approximately 26.03 linear feet. Cornelius Vanderbilt IV was an inveterate traveler and much of his writing consists of articles written for several different periodicals as he journeyed throughout the world, observing the political and social scene. He was the biographer of his mother, Grace Wilson Vanderbilt, and the collection contains memorabilia, newspaper clippings, photographs, and correspondence related to his mother’s reign as queen of New York and Newport society. There are also many photographs and clippings pertaining to Cornelius Vanderbilt IV’s career as a journalist and lecturer, as well as radio scripts from the broadcasts he made in the 1930s and 1940s.
The bulk of the collection consists of his writings. His earliest work as a cub reporter for the “New York Herald”x is contained in leather-bound scrapbooks. Other scrapbooks hold the articles he wrote as a free-lance correspondent for other eastern newspapers. Four volumes of scrapbooks contain the work he produced as owner and editor of the “Illustrated Daily News” in Los Angeles in 1923-1924. By far the largest part of his writings are to be found in the seventeen boxes of the articles he wrote from the 1920s to the 1960s for his own newsletters as well as for the regular columns for Script magazine and other periodicals such as Liberty magazine. His topics, depending upon the periodical, usually had to do with the international or national political scene or with the latest social trends. As a foreign correspondent, his family name and connections, especially in the 1930s and 1940s, gained him access to exclusive political and military groups, so he was often able to “scoop” rival journalists. He offered his readers insight into the increasingly menacing world of the 1930s and early 1940s. He was a prolific writer and often reworked the same material for the variety of publications for which he wrote. As a reporter of social trends, he was in a unique position. He characterized himself as a man of the people but moved among the wealthiest and most influential social, political, and entertainment circles. He reported on these personalities and their activities to the buyers of magazines and the subscribers to his newsletters.
The collection of clippings involves much about his own career but also pertains to publicity about his famous family, especially his mother, Grace Wilson Vanderbilt, and his father, Cornelius Vanderbilt III.
Among the photographs are various studio portraits made in the late 19th and early 20th centuries. Most of the other photographs were taken by Cornelius Vanderbilt IV during various trips throughout the world in the 1930s and 1940s.
The collection will be of interest to those researching the Vanderbilt family and to those looking into journalism of the first half of the 20th century. The writings capture the personalities, social trends, and political views of the era.
Biographical Sketch
Cornelius Vanderbilt IV, the first child of Grace Wilson Vanderbilt and Cornelius Vanderbilt III, was born in New York City on April 30, 1898. He was educated at various boys’ schools in the United States, as well as in Europe, where his parents took him on their frequent sojourns abroad. With the entrance of the United States into World War I in 1917, young Cornelius, against his parents’ wishes, enlisted in the American Expeditionary Force. He served in France as a dispatch driver and was honorably discharged in 1919.
He began work as a cub reporter for the “New York Herald” and other newspapers, then and ever afterward using the by-line Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr. Later, as a free-lance journalist, he moved westward, writing articles about the western United State for eastern newspapers. In 1923, he began the “Illustrated Daily News,” based in Los Angeles and expanded to San Francisco and Miami, but he proved a better journalist than business man and by 1926 he lost this enterprise to bankruptcy.
In the 1920s–1930s, he worked as an associate editor for the “New York Mirror,” and he began traveling extensively throughout the world as a reporter for various news organizations. His syndicated column, “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.” continued into the 1940s, along with his newsletter, “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt,” which was published in the 1940s–1960s. In the 1940s, he also wrote a column, “High Spots” for “Script” magazine. During the years from the 1930s–1960s, he wrote over two hundred articles for many publications. He also wrote twelve books, some privately printed. In 1930, his novel, “Reno” was made into a movie by the same name and was widely reviewed. Many of his other books reflected his social and professional background, including “Farewell to Fifth Avenue “ (1930), “Queen of the Golden Age” (1956), and “Man of the World: My Life on Five Continents” (1959).
During World War II he served in the military again, as a major in the United States Army Intelligence Services from 1942–1943, when he was honorably discharged because of poor health. He was awarded the Distinguished Service Cross of the FBI in 1942.
He was married seven times but had no children. His wives were: Rachael Littleton (1920–1927), Mary Logan (1928–1931), Helen Varner (1935–1940), Felize Pablos (1946–1947), Patricia Wallace (1948–1953), Ann Needham (1957–1960), and Mary Lou Gardiner Bristol (1967–1974).
On July 7, 1974, Cornelius Vanderbilt IV died in Miami and was survived by his wife, Mary Lou Vanderbilt and her two children.
- Series I—Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Correspondence—Outgoing (Box 1)
    - 1918–1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - June, 26, 1923–August 20, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - June 6, 1930–August 9, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - January 23, 1936–April 26, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - April 7, 1944–December 27, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - January 7, 1946–July 22,1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - April 17, 1950–August 19, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - May 31, 1960–August 31, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - September 7, 1965–Octtober 28, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - November 1, 1965–November 15, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - November 16, 1965–November 30, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - December 1, 1965–December 31, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - January 3, 1966–May 19, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - June 7, 1966–March 29, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence—Incoming (Box 2)
    - Adams–Aymar (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Babcock–Bennet (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Berry–Bye (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Callard–Clark (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Cohn–Curtis (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Daffin–Durkee (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Eadie–Eulau (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Fagan–Frederick (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Frooks, Dorothy–Frooks, Leighton (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gent–Gutterman (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Haggard–Hayman (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Hearst–Hitchcock (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Hoffman–Hunter (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Iconberg–Jueneman (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Kahn–Kramer (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Landis–Luria (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence—Incoming (Box 3)
    - MacDonald–Martinet (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Masters–Murray (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Nason–Norris (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - O”Brien–Oursler (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Packard–Proctor (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Randolph–Riordan (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Richardson–Ryan (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Salter–Simon (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Snook–Sweeny (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Taft–Underwood (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, III (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Vanderbilt, Grace Wilson (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Vanderbilt, Alice (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Vanderbilt, William H. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Vanderlip–Vorster (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Wagner–Wells (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Wetcott–Wright (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Yankwich–Zugsmith (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified correspondents (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letters to other Vanderbilt family members (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Series II—Writings (Box 4)
  - Writings—Articles (Box 4)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.” —, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”—, late 1930s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1939–1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1939–1940 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - “Going Places with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.”, March 18, 1941–May 21, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, February–October, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, 1930s (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, mid–1930s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, late 1930s–1940s (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, 1940s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - “High Spots,” Script Magazine, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - “High Spots,” New York Post, 1945–1946 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Publicity for Script Magazine, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1965–1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, Pp. 1–134, 1948–1954 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Notes for “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, Pp. 135–300, 1948–1954 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1949–1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1960–1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, June, 1964; September, 1964; June–October, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, January–June, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, July–December, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt”, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt” (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt” (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Documents pertaining to “Vagabonding with Vanderbilt” (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Sample copies of stationery for Vanderbilt’s travel columns (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - “The Adventures of Reginald Beaumont” (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - “America Awakes” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - “American Girls Are Changing” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - “Among the Hollywood Hostesses” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - “Another Plan of Life for the Windsors” (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - “Are Famous Biblical Miracles Characterized on Mystery Carvings on Sprout Lake Rocks?” (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - “At Billings” (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - “A ’Trailing We Shall Go” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - “Avoiding Purchasing a Newspaper” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - “The Bankers Say No War” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - “Barge Girl,” Installment One ( 2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - “Barge Girl,” Installment Two ( 2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - “Barge Girl,” Installment Three (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - “Barge Girl,” Installment Five (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - “Barge Girl,” Installment Six (incomplete) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - “The Beauty Belt” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - ”Bees Bring Fame, Riches” (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - “Behind the Scenes with Hollywood Society” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - “The Bribe” (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - “Bring Chinese Labor into Hawaii” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - “Cabarets and Night Clubs in the Far East” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - “California Comes Back Again” (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - “Can Hitler Execute This Daring Plan[?]” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - “The Charm of Our Deserts” (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - “A City That Grew Overnight” (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - “The Collapse and Come–Back of Capitalism,” Parts II & III (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - “The Commodore” (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - “The Copy Reader” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - [Count de Bonn] Untitled (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - “Czechoslovakia Tries to Gain Free Publicity” (2 copies) (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - “The Death of FDR” (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - [Delivering the Last Papers from Danzig] Untitled (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - “Dispatch to Anglo–Continental Newspapers” (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - “Dodging Bricks Instead of Shrapnel” (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - “Does Society Mock at Marriage?” (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - “Does Tutoring Build or Undermine the Young?” (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - “Don’t Be Too Good a Fellow” (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - “Don’t Give Up the Ship” (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - “D.P.R.” (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - “Dude Ranching” (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - “The Earl of Limerick’s Eccentricities—and His Bribe” (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - “Enchanting Carmel” (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - “Esperanto Among the Fashionable Florida Keys” (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - “European Militarism” (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - “Exercise—the PhD of the World” (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - “Fate Must Have My Number” (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - “F D B C” (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - “FDR’s Last Great Dream” (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - “Fifth Avenue vs. Hollywood” (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - [My Fight for Clean Journalism] Untitled (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - “Florida Must Face the Truth” (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - “From the Smoldering Ashes of Bygone Prairie Schooners” (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - “The Fun We Had” (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - “Gas Warfare” (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - “Germany Takes to the Air” (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - “Go West, Young Man” (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - “Good Food Is Where You Find It” (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - “Gossip” (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - “Half Past the Eleventh Hour” (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - “He Stopped Hitler” (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - “Hell in Spain As I Saw It” (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - “Here Girls Is Howard Hughes” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - “Here’s Where the Big Shirts Go” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - “He’s Off to South America to Bag Hirsute Appendages” (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - “The High Cost of Swank” (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - “High Spotting Florida—Socially Speaking” (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - “Highly Eligible”—Installment II (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - “Highly Eligible”—Installment III (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - “His Pal Was FDR” (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - “Hollywood Manners” (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - “How Al Capone Would Run This Country” (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - “How I Learned What They Thought of Me” (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - “How the Women of California Elected a Great Man” (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - “Hypocrisy” (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - “The Hypocrisy of Even Our Closest Friends” (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - “An Idealistic Youth” (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - “I Don’t Want To Be a War Correspondent” (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - “I Like to Live in a Trailer” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - “I Played a Hunch” (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - “I Want None of This Here” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - “I’ll Take Care of Myself Says Man Who Is 99 Today” (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - “Illegal Drug Trade Has Doubled in Canada Since Prohibition Went into Effect” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - “Immigration Policy” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - “Interviewing with Difficulties the Prince of Wales” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - “Into the Frozen North” (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - “Introducing Myself, Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.” (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - “Iribe Will Never Speak French Behind Our Back Anymore” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - “Is Japan Imperialistic and What Has She in View?” (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - “Is Roosevelt Losing His Popularity?” (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - “It Won’t Buy Everything!” (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - “Japan Behind Bolshevist Reign of Terror Says Major Hazzard, A.E.F.” (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - “Japan’s Fishing Boats” (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - [The Japanese Threat in California] Untitled (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - [Japanese War Scare] Untitled (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - “Kaiser [Wilhelm II]” (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - “Keeping California White by Peace or War,” Part I (2 copies) & Part II (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - “Labor” (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - “A Land–Lubber Takes to the Air or A Trans–Continental Straphanger” (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - “The Law and I, Rolling My House Behind Me” (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - “Let’s Never Do It Again” (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - [Lloyd George and Terence McSweeney] Untitled (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - “Liberty or Death Says Jan Syrovy” (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - “The Little Blue Piano” (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - “Lord Dunsany, the Idealist Interviewed Against His Wishes” (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - “Mayor Cryer of Los Angeles” (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - “Men, Yen and When?” (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - “Merry Miami Melody” (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - “Daniel Moran: Engineer of Big Bridges” (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - “The Most Important Man in Congress” (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - ’The Most Misunderstood Woman” (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - [Movies Are Changing the World] Untitled (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - “Mussolini” (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - “Must My Pet Hobby Be Destroyed by Publicity?” (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - “My Fabulous, Exciting Mother” (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - “My Newspaper Career” (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - “Nazi Airwaves Over the Caribbean” (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - “Newport Flings Back the Gauntlet” (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - “No Sunken Gold in the East River, So Cap Digs Goal” (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - “Nothing Was Impossible in Spain” (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - “Now It Can Be Told” (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - “The Old Mug Again” (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - “One of the Reasons British Columbia Lost Prohibition” (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - “Our Great Resourceful Territory West of the Once Impenetrable Rockies” (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - “Outwitting the Securite Nationale” (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - [Pacific Great Eastern Railway] Untitled (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - “Paradise on Steel” (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - “Paradise on Wheels” (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - “Park Avenue Where Bad Women Take Good Dogs Walking” (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - “Peace Through Patience” (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - “Pearl Harbor Couldn’t Be Prevented” (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - “A Plan of Life for the Windsors” (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - “Plans World Tour at 78” (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - “Play Area Named for Lillian Wald” (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - “Eleanor Powell” (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - “Pointers from the Past Week’s News” (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - “Prairie Town Honors Maker of Plow Today” (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - [The Presidential Campaign, 1936] Untitled (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - “The Public Be Served” (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - “The Public Be Served,” # 2,3, & 4 (2 copies of each) (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - “The Pulse of America,” #1,2,3 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - “Puppet Love,” Part 1 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - “Puppet Love,” Part 2 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - “Puppet Love,” Part 3 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - “Puppet Love,” Part 4 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - “Puppet Love,” Part 5 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - “Purse Peeking—the New Hollywood Game” (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - “Quit Grumbling About America” (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - “Radio Station KRLH” (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - “The Reception on the Sound” (2 copies) (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - “The Reno Racket” (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - “The Renaissance of Reno” (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - “Reporting Riots” (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - “Rollicking Reno” (2 copies) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - “Rolling Along with Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr.” (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - “Rolling Through Canada” (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - “[The Roosevelt Children] Untitled (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - “Roving Reporter,” Chapter III (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - “Roving Reporter,” Chapter IV (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - “Roving Reporter” Chapter V (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - “Roving Reporter,” Chapter VI (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - “The Russia Nobody Wants To Hear About” (2 copies) (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - “Saints and Angels in Competition” (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - “The Sea Hornet” (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - “Shall California Remain White[?]” (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - “Smart America” (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - “Social Overhead” (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - “Society Comes of Age” (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - “A Soldier of Freedom” (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - “The Soviets New Foreign Minister” (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - “Soy Bean Features” (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - “Space Today” (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - “S.S. Flotilla in New York Harbor” (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - “Story of the Evening Star” (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - “Thank Heaven for Our Great Middle West” (2 copies) (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Judge Bartlett (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Nora Bayes (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Beebee (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Berand (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - W.J. Bryan (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Byrd (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - “Thumbnail Sketches” for the New York Graphic: (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Lord Camrose (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Princess Cantacuzene (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Carnegie (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Carol of Romania (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Earl Carroll (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Clarence Chamberlain (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Charlie Chaplin (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - W.A.Clark (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Clemenceau (Box 13, Folder 26)